おす
Yo...
お疲れ様です　兄貴
Good afternoon, Aniki.
どうしたんだ　幸村　その格好
Yukimura, what's with that outfit?
It's Become-a-Real-Man Training, Version 2!
真の男になるための特訓バージョン2だ
Though my skills remain immature,
I shall be your devoted servant.
未熟者ですが　精進致します
No, no, it's not a
maturity issue; you're a girl!
いやいやいや　未熟もなにも幸村は女だろう
真の男は性別など超越した存在なのです
A true man is someone who transcends biology.
Correct, Yukimura. Even
if you are biologically female,
そのとおりだ　幸村
真の男の魂を持っていれば
例え生物的に女であろうが 真の男になることが出来るのだ
if you have the soul of a true man,
you can become a true man!
はい　見ていてください兄貴
Yes. I promise you, Aniki,
I shall become a true man like you.
わたくしは必ずや兄貴のような真の男になって見せます
BE MY FRIEND
Be My Friend
知らないフリしたって
Yeah, you played dumb
BE MYSELF
Be My Side
But I saw right through you
全部気付いてるよ
もう一歩
I'll walk another step toward your side
君の隣に行こう
その手にだって届きそうさ
I bet I can even reach your hand
"Haganai NEXT"
想像しちゃダメ
It's more than I imagined... every
day's a roller coaster
ジェットコースターな毎日
引き締めて前を向いて
I always barreled ahead with everything I had
いつも駆け抜けたら
ずっと続きはしないね
Our time won't last forever, now will it?
僕らの時間は今しかないから
Now is all we have, so let's make
sure we remember this moment
この瞬間刻みづけよう
BE MY FRIEND
Be My Friend
Yeah, you played dumb
知らないフリしたって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
But I saw right through you
全部気付いてるよ
I'll walk another step toward your side
もう一歩
君の隣に行こう
受け止めるように
So I can take your hand
Be My Friend
BE MY FRIEND
Yeah, I'm always gazing at the sky
見上げてばかりだって
Be My Side
BE MYSELF
But I'm still drawn to it
憧れてる今も
One more time! I'll reach out
to you as many times as you need
もう一回
何度でも手を伸ばそう
あの星だって届きそうさ
I bet I can even reach that star
"That  Kind of Play Is Not Allowed... and...
My Worldview Is Disturbed When You Are Around"
Okay, I understand your determination, but...
幸村の決意はわかった
わかったけど　なんで執事
Why a butler?
A butler is the quintessential
"capable man," obviously.
出来る男といえば執事だろ
Really?
そうか
I think it's fine. Girls in
butler costumes are cute anyway.
いいじゃない　執事服姿の女の子って可愛いんだし
True, and pretty girl butlers
are popular these days.
そうですね　最近美少女執事って流行ってますし
Yeah, like Kokonoe Mebaru-chan from
Chicken Butler and Mayonnaise, you know?
あれでしょう
「チキン執事とマヨネーズ」の九重メバルちゃんとかでしょう
True, the hottest item lately
probably is Mebaru from Chiki Mayo.
確かに最近一番熱いのはチキマヨのメバルんですかね
It's super-cute how even
though she always puts on airs,
メバルちゃん　普段はつんつんしているのに
she's actually kind of a goof-up and
she's constantly letting her guard down.
ちょっとドジっ娘で　隙が多いところが超可愛いのよね
It's also magnificent how naturally
erotic the things she does are!
行動がナチュラルにえろいところも素晴らしいですね
The way she gets covered in
mayonnaise every two seconds,
事あるごとにマヨネーズまみれになっちゃうところなんてもう
it's like, "You're asking for it,
aren't you, girl?!" You know?
この女誘ってやがんのかって感じですし
Mebaru-chan's so cute!
可愛いわよね　メバルちゃん
She gets Rika's moe going!
ちょう萌えますよね
You've got good taste, putting
Yukimura-san in a butler suit, Yozora-sempai.
幸村さんに執事服を着せるとは
なかなかいいセンスしてますね　夜空先輩
I screwed up again.
また失敗した
That all went over my head, but
I'll wear the clothes Anego gave me
よくわかりませんが
姉御に頂いたこの服で一生懸命兄貴にご奉仕致します
to serve you with everything I have.
Uh-huh... Well, do your best, I guess.
そうか　まあ　頑張ってくれ
Hey, Rika, is that one of those
so-called "boys' love games"?
なあ　理科　それって「ボーイズラブゲーム」ってやつか
Yes, Rika thought she'd try to get
through some of her game backlog.
はい　ちょっと積みゲーを消化してしまおうかと思いまして
Anthem for
Paradise
Ayakashi
Teenage Life
Are those all BL games?
それ全部BLゲームなのか
No, there are normal RPGs,
shooters, and otomege, too!
いいえ　普通のRPGとかシューティングとか
乙女ゲーもありますよ
What are "otomege"?
乙女ゲーというのは何だ
They're like "gal games" for girls.
女の子向けのギャルゲーみたいなものですよ
Th-This is... that cursed Semoponume!
こ　これは
Sparkling School Life
あの忌まわしきせもぽぬめ
Is it a relative of Sparkling
School or something, then?
これはやっぱり　キラスクの親戚かなんかなのか
Well deduced! This is the otomege
version of Sparkling School Life,
お察しのとおり　これはきらめきスクールライフの乙女ゲー版で
where the main character's and
target characters' genders are flipped.
主人公と攻略キャラの性別を逆転させたガールズバージョン
It's the "Girls Version," so
it's "Girl School" for short.
通称「ガルスク」なのです
There are all kinds of games in this world, huh?
世の中いろんなゲームがあるものだな
You don't seem very interested.
あんまり興味なさそうですね
I'm not. It's related to that crap
game, so it's bound to be crap too.
ああ　ないな　あのくそゲーの親戚だ
どうせくそゲーなのだろう
I can't let that slide!
聞き捨てならないわね
I've never played
Girl School, but it pisses me off
「ガルスク」はやったことないけど
それでも「キラスク」の妹分みたいなゲームをディスられるとむかつくわ
to hear you dis a game that's
essentially Sparkling School's little sister!
To dis Girl School is to dis my little sister...
「ガルスク」をディスるってことはあたしの妹を
Yes, it is to dis Kobato-chan!
そう　小鳩ちゃんをディスると同じことなのよ
Kobato doesn't have anything to do with this.
小鳩は関係ねえだろう
Still, I don't like people rejecting
something just based on looks.
でもまあ　内容を知りもせず否定するのは俺も好きじゃないけどな
You're with them?
小鷹まで
Fine, I'll attack it after I've
played it, then. You can't object to that.
わかった　ならばプレイしてから叩いてやる
それなら文句はないな
Sparkling School Life
Sparkling School Life: Girls Version F...
きらめきスクールライフ　ガールズバージョン　フォ…
Name
Hey! Why'd you skip the opening?!
ちょっと　なんでオープニングを飛ばすのよ
It's a drag.
たるい　名前か
A name, huh?
It's traditional to play under
your own name, Sempai.
自分の名前で遊ぶのが基本ですよ　先輩
But the main character is a bitch
who hits on all the guys at once, right?
主人公は複数の男に手を出しまくるビッチなんだろう
Maybe I should play under Meat's name...
ここは肉の名前にするか
Why me?!
なんであたしなのよ
Bitch play is fun too, but why
not limit yourself to one boy
ビッチプレイも楽しいですが
まずは一人の男の子に狙いをしぼった
and play as a pure-hearted
girl for your first time?
純情キャラでいくのはどうですか
Hmm, in that case...
そういうことなら
Mikazuki
Yohechiborake! Yohechiborake!
A weird name for a weird girl!
Yohechiborake
よへちぼらけだって　よへちぼらけ
あんたに相応しい変な名前ね
- I didn't realize she was still
bitter about the "Semoponume" thing...
- Yohechiborake!
こいつせもぽぬめのことまだ根に持ってたのか
So not cool!
よへちぼらけ　かっこ悪い
Sena-sempai.
星奈先輩
Why are you throwing cold water
せっかく乙女ゲーの楽しさを布教しようとしているのに
on Rika's efforts to spread the otomege gospel?
どうして水を差すようなまねをするのですか
Oh, er, well...
あ　いや　そうれは　そのう
Why?
どうしてですか
U-Um... I'm sorry.
え　えっと　御免なさい
What are you apologizing for?
何を謝っているのですか
Rika is politely asking you
to tell her why you did that.
理科はなぜあんなことをしたのか教えてくださいと尋ねているのですよ
S-Scary!
こ　こわぇ
Mikazuki                                 Yozora
"My name is Mikazuki Yozora!
私の名前はみかづきよぞら
Starting today, I'm a high school
freshman here at Sparkling Academy!
今日からこの「きらめき学園」に通う高校一年生
Ah, the spring breeze feels so nice!"
う～ん　春風が気持ちいいなぁ
Spring breeze?!
"I'm just an ordinary, average girl, but
I'd love to have a wonderful school life.
どこにでもいるごく普通の女の子の私だけど
素敵な高校生活を送りたいな
This hope swells in my breast
そんな希望に胸を膨らませ
as I head through the gate
in a swirl of cherry blossoms."
桜吹雪の舞う校門を潜り抜ける
Hope swells in your breast?!
You don't even have any breasts to swell!
希望に胸を膨らませ
あんた膨らませる胸ないじゃん
What was that for, Spring Breeze?!
何すんのよ　この春風
- I'll kill you.
- It's okay, you'll get accustomed to it.
殺す
まあまあ　そのうち慣れますって
"Ouch!"
いった～い
"I'm sorry, I was daydreaming.
Here, can you stand?"
ごめんね　ぼーっとしてたものだから
ほら　立てるかい
Who is this boy?
誰だ　この男は
Shinomori Ouji. He's a rising
freshman, just like the player!
篠乃杜桜路　主人公と同じ新入生ですよ
He's the heir to the Shinomori Conglomerate,
篠乃杜財閥の御曹子で
and he's really popular with the girls.
女子生徒からの人気が凄く高いんです
"I hope we can both lead wonderful school lives."
お互い　素敵な学園生活を送れるといいね
"That boy was really cool...
かっこいい人だったなぁ
If I got to meet someone like that first thing,
入学早々あんな人と知り合いになれるなんて
I think my days here will be nice and rosy!"
私の学園生活　バラ色の予感
Nice and rosy!
From now on I'm calling you
Rosy instead of Spring Breeze.
やっぱりあんた「春風」じゃなくて「バラ色」って呼ぶわね
This girl with flowerbeds for brains is not me!
こんな脳内お花畑の女は私じゃない
I'm switching back to Yohechiborake!
よへちぼらけに戻せ
Now, now, calm down. It's just a game.
まあ　落ち着いてください
これはゲームなんですから
"Hey, do you know Shinomori-kun?"
ねえねえ　あなた篠乃杜くんと知り合いなの
Who is this pushy broad?!
なんだ　こいつは馴れ馴れしい
Fuyuki Yoko. Apparently she
sits next to the player in class.
冬木陽子　主人公のクラスメイトで
隣の席の子らしい
So, when do I get the option to tell her to die?
で　この女に死ねという選択肢は何時出てくるのだ
Why?!
何でだよ
This girl suddenly starts chatting up
someone she doesn't know like they're friends.
見ず知らずの人間に親しげに話しかけてくるような女だぞ
She seems like a bitch,
just like Fujibayashi Akari.
藤林明と同じビッチ臭がする
Hey! Akari is a really nice girl!
ちょっと　明はとてもいい子なんだからね
"Let's be friends, okay, Yozora?"
これから仲良くやろうね　よぞら
"Sure, nice to meet you!"
うん　よろしくね
Betrayer. I just know this girl's a betrayer.
裏切る　この女は絶対に裏切る
Today I dress up!
This Week's Plans
Exercise
Studying
Fashion
Art
Rest
She's a hopeless loser, isn't she?
絶望的な駄目女だな
I'll start by building up her grades.
とりあえずは学力からだ
Today I study!
Studying
Okay, now we're talking!
よし　その調子だ
"Hmmm, this question's hard..."
う～ん……　この問題難しいなぁ
Moron! She won't make it on her
own in life if she's getting tripped up
馬鹿者め　一年生の一学期に出てくる問題で躓いてるようでは
by first-semester freshman homework!
この先一人でやって行けないぞ
"You look like you're having trouble.
Want me to explain that to you?"
困ってるようだな　なんなら俺が教えてやろうか
Boy with glasses FTW!
メガネ男子来た
Is this the Girl School version
of Yukiko? Not a very impressive guy.
こいつがガルスク版の有希子なの
さえないやつね
His name is Suzutsuki Touma.
Apparently he's the smartest one in your grade.
名前は涼月冬馬
学年一の秀才らしい
Why not let him teach you?
いいんじゃないか　勉強を教えてもらえば
"You're always studying in the library, right?
キミ　いつも図書室で勉強しているだろ
So... I've been thinking about you."
それが……　ちょっと気になっていてね
Th-Thinking?! Four-Eyes may look
serious, but he's really disgraceful!
き　気になる
真面目そうな顔して　なんて破廉恥なメガネだ
Thanks. Please explain it.
You're in my way, so get lost!
"You're in my way, so get lost!"
邪魔だからあっちいって
"I admire you for wanting to
solve the problem all by yourself.
あくまで自分の力で問題を解こうとするその姿勢感心だな
But I think asking people for help
once in a while is a sensible tactic.
だが　時には人に頼るのも合理的な手段だと思うぞ
Feel free to call on me if you ever need me."
もしも必要になったら呼んでくれ
You are now able to ask Suzutsuki Touma out on a date.
Ugh, what a pain.
面倒なことになったな
From now on I'd better avoid
the library and do something else.
次からは図書室を避けて別のことをしよう
Today I exercise!
Exercise
Studying
Fashion
Art
Rest
All right! Now this is me!
よし　これでこそ私だ
You wasted all your chances at dates, though...
デートのチャンスはすべて棒に振ったはな
This character's school
life is too painful to watch.
この主人公の学園生活痛々し過ぎて見てられません
Wow, Yozora's just sad.
何て残念な夜空
You scum have a death wish, coming
after me when I've got a 380 battle level!
戦闘力380の私に絡んでくるとは
命知らずのゴミ共め
Why? Why isn't the "attack" option coming up?!
なぜだ　どうして攻撃の選択肢が出ない
Because this isn't that
kind of game, obviously...
そりゃそういうゲームじゃないからだろう
"Ugh, guys like you seriously make me wanna puke."
チッ　てめえらみたいなのを見るとマジでヘドが出るぜ
"Bastard!"
てめぇ……
"Get him!"
やっちまえ
"You're Mikazuki Yozora, right?"
あんた　みかづきよぞらだろ
"How do you know my name?"
どうして私の名前を
"You are famous, you know."
そりょあ有名人だからな
"The name's Nagatani Eiji.
オレは永谷英二ってんだ
This ain't the place for elite
types like you to wander around in.
ここは　あんたみたいなエリートがうろつく場所じゃねぇ
Go on home."
とっとと帰りな
"You are now able to ask
Nagatani Eiji out on a date."
Maybe I'll ask him out!
こいつを誘ってみるか
So is this your type, Yozora-sempai?
夜空先輩　やっぱりこういう男の子がタイプなんですか
No! But just leveling
forever is boring, isn't it?!
違う　このまま単純作業　続けてもつまらないだろう
So...
だから
I can't really handle guys like that.
俺そういうタイプ苦手だなあ
Their eyes are scary,
and they're curt with everyone...
目付き悪くて怖いし　ぶっきらぼうで愛想はないし
- You're one to talk!
- Like you can talk!
- You have no right to talk, Sempai.
お前が言うな
あんたが言うな
先輩が言わないでください
"Huh? Next Sunday?"
え　次の日曜日…
"Right. Let's meet...
Um, how about at the batting cages?"
そう　場所は……
えっと　バッティングセンターでどう
"That's fine, I guess..."
まぁ　別にいいけどよ
"Okay, it's a date."
じゃあ　決まりね
"You're pretty good."
やるじゃねーか
"Anyone can do this much!"
このくらい当然よ
"You... did your hair different today, huh?"
…今日は髪型が違うんだな
"Hmm? Did you say something?"
え　なにか言った
な　なんでもねーよ
"It was nothing."
Huh, he's pretty observant for a Yankee.
ええ　ヤンキーの分際でなかなか気が付くじゃないの
Oh, if only Kodaka-sempai
were such a keen observer...
小鷹先輩にもこれくらいの目敏さがあれば
Of what?
何がだよ
Hairstyles! When a girl changes
her hairstyle, you have to mention it!
髪型の話ですよ
女の子が髪型を変えたらちゃんと指摘してあげる
With a compliment, if possible!
出来れば褒めるがよし
When you got a haircut I told
you it suited you, right Yozora?
夜空が髪切った時　似合ってるって言ったよな　俺
いきなりそんな話を持ち出すな
Don't just bring that up out of nowhere! Hmph!
So you complimented Yozora-sempai...
夜空先輩のことは褒めてあげてたんですか
Speaking of hairstyles, you're
changing yours constantly lately, aren't you?
髪型といえば　お前この間からちょくちょく変えてるよな
If you noticed, you should've said so!
気付いてたんなら言えよ
You never reacted,
so Rika was afraid that to you,
全然反応してくれないから
先輩は理科のことを道端の石ころ程度にしか認識してないじゃないかって
she was about as noticeable
as a pebble on the roadside!
She was really depressed!
本気でへこんでたんですよ
S-Sorry!
すまん
But duh, of course I'm always watching you.
つうか　俺がお前のこと見てないわけがないだろうが
じゃなきゃ何を仕出かすかわかんないからな
'Cause who knows what you'll do unsupervised...
Hmph! It's too late to win Rika over with that!
今更そんなことを言ったって遅いんですからね
Well, too bad for you, Sempai.
惜しかったですね　先輩
What do you mean?
惜しいって何がだ
If you'd complimented Rika, your affection
points would've gone through the roof!
ちゃんと褒めてたら好感度上がり捲くりでしたよ
Rika's difficulty rating is extremely
low, if she does say so herself!
自分で言うのもなんですが　理科なんて攻略難易度超低いですからね
If this were an eroge, we'd be
going at it like rabbits by now!
エロゲーだったら今頃もエッチし捲くりですよ
You'd clear Rika's flags
and be cleared for launch!
フラグビンビン　先輩もビンビン
Why should I have to win
affection points from you?
何で俺がお前の好感度上げなきゃいけない
Goddammit!
ガッデム
H-Hey... Rika?
おい　理科
Rika's getting confused now, so she's going
to her lab to bask in the afterglow for a while.
混乱してきたのでちょっと理科室で賢者タイムに突入してきます
A-Afterglow?
け　賢者タイム
Shiguma Rika is to be pitied.
志熊理科　憐れなやつ
"Another fun day, huh?"
今日も楽しかったね
"Y-Yeah..."
そ…そうだな……
ど　どうしよう
Oh no... Do you... think maybe he likes me?
こいつはもしかして私のことが好きなんじゃないか
He definitely has some feelings for you.
明らかに好意は持ってるだろうな
So I was right?
やっぱり　そうなのか
"Look, Yozora. What do you
say we stop seein' each other?
なぁよぞら
オレたち　もう会うのやめねぇか
You're the school star. They even
made you student council president.
よぞら　うちの学園のスターで今じゃ生徒会長だ
If you keep hangin' out with a punk like me,
オレみたいな不良と連んでたらお前の評判に泥を塗っちまう
It'll wreck your reputation."
"You wuss! Who cares what
other people decide to think of me?!
このヘタレが
世間が勝手に作り上げた評判など知ったことか
I'll decide who I want to
be with! So you stay with me!"
自分が一緒にいたい相手は自分で決める
だから　これからも私と一緒にいろ
Oh no, Yozora suddenly seems cool...
どうしよう　夜空がかっこよく見える
Anego...
姉御
If this keeps going... they might...
これはこのまま行けばもしかしたら
"I got into a first-rate university,
but I didn't manage to get close to anyone.
一流大学に進学することは出来たけど
誰とも仲良くなれなかった
It was a lonely three years.
寂しい三年間だったな……
Maybe I should've been kinder to people..."
もっと人に優しくすれば良かったのかな
なんでこうなんのよ　英二はどうなったのよ
Why did it turn out this way?! What about Eiji?!
どこかで重要なフラグを立て損なったんでしょうね
At some point you must
have failed to clear a key flag.
After all, you never interacted
with the other boys, or Yoko.
ほかの男子キャラや陽子と交流してませんでしたから
Oh.
そうか
Please don't get too down about it...
Failure is half the fun of gaming.
えっと　あまり気を落とさないでください
失敗もゲームの醍醐味ですよ
Make use of what you
learned to take another crack at it!
今回の反省を活かしてリベンジしましょう
No, I'm done.
いや　もういい
If this is what happens when I live
my life the way I want, then that's that.
思い通りに生きた結果がこれなら　仕方ない
Sorry I called it a crap game.
Girl School was pretty fun, really.
くそゲー呼ばわりして悪かった
「ガルスク」なかなか面白かったぞ
Plus...
それに
I've got enough friendless,
wussy Yankees in my real life.
友達がいないへタレヤンキーなら現実で間に合ってるからな
Yo.
おす
Hello, Kodaka-sempai.
こんにちは　小鷹先輩
Hi. You changed your hairstyle, huh?
髪型変えたんだな
That's it?!
それだけ
Jeez, I said something
about your hair, didn't I?
なんだよ　ちゃんと髪型指摘したぞ
Yes, Rika changed her hairstyle.
確かに髪型は変えましたよ
But you've noticed other
things too, right? Haven't you?
けど　ほかにも気付いたことあるでしょう
ありますよね
Here... ta-da!
ほら
A haircut?
髪切った
Wrong!
切ってねえよ
I know, I know, I was just joking.
わかってるよ　ちょっとした冗談だ
もう　先輩ったら意地悪なんだから
Oh, Sempai, you're so mean.
You changed hairbands!
髪留め変えた
Wrong!
変えてねえよ
So, what's up with the
blonde look? You going delinquent?
で　その金髪はどうしたんだよ
ぐれたのか
No, Rika is not. She merely
wanted to try coloring it.
違います　ちょっと染めてみただけです
That's bad for your hair, you know.
髪が痛むぞ
Not to worry! Rika used a
special dye she created herself!
ご安心を　理科特製の染毛剤を使いましたから
You made it?
お前の
Rika is proud of this one: there's
almost zero fading or damage to the hair!
自信作なんですよ　これ
髪へのダメージや色落ちがほぼゼロなんです
Not only that: this
outstanding product allows you
その上専用の薬を使えば　すぐに黒髪に戻せる優れもの
to go right back to your natural
black if you use the antidote!
Amazing, isn't it?!
すごいでしょう
I guess so...
ああ　まあなあ
But you know, it's like, your
inventions are so... unexciting.
しかしあれだな　お前の発明って
地味だよな
地味ですと
"Unexciting"?!
Yeah. Useful computer programs,
super-long-lasting light bulbs,
便利なコンピュータプログラムだの
半永久的に使える電球だの
electric pots that can boil
water without a heat source,
熱源がなくても沸かせる電気鍋だの
fully automatic beetle-raising tanks...
全自動甲虫飼育籠だの
It's like they're all about utility, and
they've got no sparkle, no romance...
何か実用性重視で華がないつうか　ロマンがないつうか
Then what kind of invention do you want?!
だったらどんな発明ならいいんですか
Well... Hey, I know, how about
one of those giant robots you like?
例えば
ほら　お前の好きな巨大ロボットとか
いきなり国家プロジェクト級の物を挙げたきよった
And he starts off with a
national-government-level project!
Okay, what about a fifth-dimensional pocket?
じゃあ五次元ポケットとか
巨大ロボットより遥かに難易度上がってますわよ
The difficulty factor just shot
up far beyond a giant robot there.
All right, maybe a flashlight that
can make stuff bigger or smaller,
だったら物を小さくしたり大きくしたりする懐中電灯とか
or a cloth you can wrap
around broken things to fix them,
壊れたものをもとに戻す風呂敷とか
or a jelly you can eat and
understand all languages...
食べたらどんな国の言葉でもわかるようになる蒟蒻とか
Oh, hey! How do you feel about time machines?
ああそうだ
タイムマシンはどうだ
Ti?!
Okay, Rika made a time machine!
というわけで作ってきましたタイムマシン
Huh?
Time machine?
タイムマシン
Can you use that thing to
go to the past and future?
それで過去とか未来に行けちゃうの
Unfortunately only your consciousness
can go, and you can only go to the past.
残念ながら行けるのは意識だけ
それも過去限定です
You're kidding, right?
冗談だろう
Try it, then, if you don't believe Rika.
嘘だと思うなら試してみてくださいよ
Rika will set it to bring
you back after five minutes.
5分経ったら戻ってくるようにセットして置きますね
O-Okay...
Aniki...
兄貴
That thing better be safe.
本当に大丈夫なんだろうな
You can trust mad scientist Shiguma Rika!
狂気の発明家　志熊理科を信じてください
That made me more worried...
余計不安になったんだが
Don't sweat the small stuff. Okay, please
focus on the time you want to go back to.
細かいことは気にせずに
はい
先輩の戻りたい時間を強くイメージしてください
The time I want to go back to...
戻りたい時間
Is this?
ここは
No way.
まさか
What are you mumbling about?
何をぶつぶつ言ってるんだ
S-Seriously?
マ　マジかよ
What is it, Taka?
何だよ　鷹
Huh? What? What?!
Is something wrong?
どうかしたのか
Nah, it's nothing.
いや　なんでもない
You're so weird.
変なの
Well, whatever. Okay, remember
we promised to meet tomorrow.
まあいや　それじゃ明日約束だからな
It's true. I'm in that day!
間違いない　ここはあの日だ
See you later, Taka.
じゃあな　鷹
Yozora, wait!
待ってくれ夜空
How do you know my name?
どうして俺の名前を
I'm moving away the day after tomorrow!
俺　あさってこの町から引っ越すんだ
I won't be back for ten years.
戻ってくるのは10年後になる
So tomorrow's my last chance to see you!
だからお前と会えるのは明日が最後になる
Taka...
鷹
I'm sorry!
御免
For leaving without saying anything.
黙っていなくなって
But even if we can't see each
other, we'll always be friends!
でも離れてても俺たちはずっと友達だ
この町に戻ってくるまで忘れてたくせに
You forgot about her until
you came back, you jerk.
I'll never forget you!
お前のことは絶対に忘れない
You couldn't even remember
your best friend's face, you jerk.
親友の顔も思い出せなかったくせに
I'm sorry, Yozora!
御免　夜空
I'm really sorry.
本当に御免
Not good enough.
駄目だ
I'll never forgive you!
絶対に許さない　死ね
Die!
I am known as the demon As-taro!
我が名は魔人明日太郎
Huh?!
Kodaka, you're mine!
小鷹　貴様は私の物だ
Please forgive me!
許してくれ
Yozora!
夜空
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか
Oh, right... I came back to
this world after five minutes.
そっか　5分経ったからもとの世界に
Rika apologizes, Sempai. She lied
when she said this was a time machine.
すみません先輩
これはタイムマシンだというのは嘘です
The truth is, it's a sleep-aid
device Rika added a hypnotic effect to
実は睡眠誘導装置に催眠術の効果を加えたもので
so it lets you dream whatever
you want by wishing for it strongly.
強く念じることで
好きな夢を見ることができるというアイテムなんです
So that was... a dream?
じゃあ　今のは　夢
Rika only wanted to pull a little prank on you,
ちょっとしたいたずらのつもりだったんですけど
but it sounded like she ended up
giving you a terrible nightmare...
なんだか凄い悪夢を見せてしまったようで
Rika is very sorry.
どうもすみませんでした
Nah, I'm sorry too, for calling
your inventions unexciting.
ああいや　俺もお前の発明を地味とか言って悪かったよ
And that machine is amazing!
それにすげえよ　その機械
Things got weird at the end, but
I really did get to feel like a time traveler.
最後は変なことになったけど
本当にタイムトラベル気分が味わえたからな
You let me tell her what I didn't get
to before, even if it was in a dream.
お陰で夢とは言え　伝えられなかったことをちゃんと伝えられた
So you managed to go to
the past within the dream, then?
ということは　夢の中で過去に行くことはできたんですね
Yeah, ten years in the past.
10年前にな
Ten years, I see...
10年前ですか
Hey, Kodaka, I have a question for you.
ねえ小鷹　一つ聞きたいんだけど
Okay, what is it?
なんだ
What was Yozora doing in
your dream of ten years ago?
10年前のあんたの夢に何で夜空が出てくるの
光ったはずの星
A stray cloud blocks my view
迷った雲が邪魔して
Of the star I know should be shining there
見えなくなる
What should I believe in?
何を信じたらいい
I was on my way to breaking
不安定すぎる世界で
The treasure bred in this all too changeable world
育った宝物壊しかけてた
Because I was afraid of losing it
なくすのが怖くて
Those days of sighing "This is absurd"
不条理だって
ため息つき
どうにかどうで足掻いてた日々
And flailing inside my birdcage
We were gazing up at the same sky
同じ空を見上げてたんだ
僕らは
君の手を握った時
When I gripped your hand,
you gripped back, didn't you?
握り返してくれたね
These joined hands are stronger than any wings
繋がったこの手は
どんな羽より強いんだ
We can fly higher even without wings
翼だってなくったって
もっと高く飛べるから
So I know we'll be okay trying now
きっと今なら大丈夫
Let's grab the stars twinkling in the sky
大空輝く星を掴もう
おい　鷹　今回俺たちが予告担当だぞ
Hey, Taka, we're in
charge of the preview this time.
何か10年後が妙なことになってるけど
Things ten years from now got
kinda weird. I wonder what'll happen?
どうなるんだろうな
とりあえず　次回のサブタイは
Well, I hear the title of the next
episode is "Unbreakable Strange-Girl."
「奇行少女は傷付かない」っていうらしい
"Unbreakable Strange-Girl"
ひどいタイトルだな
ていうか「奇行少女」って誰だ
Awful title, huh?
And who's the "Strange-Girl," anyway?
空じゃねえ
俺は変な行動なんてしない
I'd guess you.
I don't do strange stuff!
いや　男装していじめっ子と喧嘩するのは普通に奇行だろう
Most people'd call dressing like a
boy and fighting with bullies "strange."
鷹の意地悪
That was mean, Taka.